# **Leroy James Rosales**

leroyrosales.com / leroyrosales@gmail.com / 512-517-5895 / linkedin.com/in/leroyrosales

# **Summary**

I'm a self-motivated and self-taught frontend web developer. I've been a freelance WordPress developer for eight years and love to work with people of all disciplines and talents. My passions are web security, web accessibility, and loving my work.

### **Professional Experience**

### Front-end Web Developer, University of Texas at Austin

June 2018 to Present, Austin, TX

Front-end web developer in Austin for the Office of the President and University Communications at the University of Texas at Austin.

#### Office of the President:

- Manage Drupal codebase and site security for the Office of the President, University Communications, Campus Carry sites
- Manage WordPress codebase and site security for the UT News, UT Tower, and UT Brand sites
- Redesigned and developed the UT SXSW 2020 site
- Work daily with a design team to maintain UT branding online, and design and develop stories for UT News
- Designed and developed the Apollo 11 UT news feature, created a manageable template for future long-form content
- Weekly discussions with stakeholders on various project statuses, expectations, and priorities
- Consult with other UT developers on maintenance and development of the core UT Austin site, and related projects

#### Office of Admissions:

- Manage Drupal codebase and site security for the Office of Admissions site
- Developed and designed email marketing campaign for prospective students of the University, helped achieve goal of raising enrollment to the university
- Worked with a third-party design team to redesign and develop the Office of Financial Aid site
- Designed and developed the First-Generation Longhorn initiative site
- Designed and developed the Career Services (now Career Engagement) website

# Associate Partner & Lead Developer, Austinite Web And Design

October 2015 to June 2018, Austin, TX

Lead developer in Austin for Austininte Web And Design.

- Projected managed various client projects from site redesigns to site consultations
- Designed and developed custom WordPress themes and plugins
- Managed WordPress security, codebases, and updates for various clientele
- Consulted with third-party designers on project look and feels, mood boards, and overall design and development strategies

### **Skills**

WordPress

Twig Templating/Twig for WordPress JavaScript

PHP

Jekyll

Sass/SCSS/CSS

Tailwind CSS

Bootstrap

Foundation

Git/Github

React

Gatsby

Drupal

Gulp

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

### Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Studio Art, University of Texas at Austin

# Awards &

### Recognition

### **The Best Higher Education**

#### Websites of 2019

Mighty Citizen

https://www.mightycitizen.com/ insights/articles/the-best-higher-education-websites-weve-seen-in-2019

# University Excellence in Communications Awards 2019

University of Texas at Austin Cross-University Collaboration award for First-Generation Longhorns Celebration Day Campaign

# Professional Experience, continued

### **Contract Web Developer, Austin Web And Design**

November 2012 to October 2015, Austin, TX

Head web developer in Austin for Austin Web And Design. Generally doing everything from creating design mockups, wireframing, and client communication.

- Trained employees on best practices in web development.
- Also trained employees on installing, using, and modifying WordPress.
- Upon project completion per client, trained each client in how to effectively use WordPress and update their site.

#### Student Teacher Assistant, University of Texas at Austin

August 2012 to Februrary 2014, Austin, TX

Designed, maintained, and developed sites for the professors and faculty at the University of Texas at Austin.

- Created the WordPress template for the Department of Psychology at UT (http://labs.la.utexas.edu/).
- Animated several educational videos for the classroom.
- Produced instructional videos for other coworkers on how to use InDesign, WordPress, and other Content Management Systems.

### Technical Advisor/Team Manager, Apple Inc.

January 2009 to August 2012, Austin, TX

Trained to help customers over the phone with different Mac hardware, software, and iPhone support.

- Was on a six-month manager rotation for a team of twenty people.
- Managed team members and communicated best practices during team meetings.